Thai lyrics from Kajsyt http://youtu.be/hgA0_JX84Zw
Romanization via http://www.thai2english.com/
Translation from Snow Queen DNAS http://youtu.be/CxkWcOwxPQc
Sung by Gam Wichayanee
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
หิมะสีขาว เป็นประกาย ใน ราตรี
hì-má sĕe kăao bpen bprà-gaai nai raa-dtree
The white snow glows in the night
not a footprint to be seen
ไม่มี รอยเท้า ยาม ที่ มอง
mâi mee roi táo yaam têe mong
No footprints when seeing
A kingdom of isolation,
ใน ดินแดนอ้างว้างร้าง ผู้คน
nai din daen âang wáang ráang pôo kon
In the isolated kingdom, without people
and it looks like I'm the queen
มี เพียง เรา นี้ ที่ ครอบครอง
mee piang rao née têe krôp krong
There is only me who possess it
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
ดั่ง มี พายุ ซ่อน อยู่ ภายใน หมุนเวียน ว่าย
dàng mee paa-yú sôn yòo paai nai mŭn wian wâai
It's like there's a storm hiding inside me, swirling and rotating
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
ถึง ต้าน เท่าไร ฉัน ก็ ห้าม ไม่ได้
tĕung dtâan tâo rai chăn gôr hâam mâi dâai
How hard I tried to resist it, I can't stop it
Don't let them in, don't let them see
อย่า เปิด ใจ ไป · อย่า ให้ เขา เห็น
yàa bpèrt jai bpai · yàa hâi kăo hĕn
Don't open mind, don't let them see
Be the good girl you always had to be
ต้อง เป็น คนดี ที่ เขา สอน ให้ เป็น
dtông bpen kon dee têe kăo sŏn hâi bpen
You must be the good one like how you are taught to be
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
ปกปิด ในใจ · อย่า ให้ เขา รู้
bpòk bpìt nai jai · yàa hâi kăo róo
Concealed in mind, don't let them know
Well, now they know!
สุดท้าย ก็ รู้
sùt táai gôr róo
Finally, they know
Let it go, let it go!
ปล่อย มัน ไป · อย่าง ที่ เป็น
bplòi man bpai · yàang têe bpen
Let it go, as it should be
Can't hold it back any more!
ไม่อาจจะ เก็บ อีกต่อไป
mâi àat jà gèp èek dtòr bpai
Can't keep it any more
Let it go, let it go!
ปล่อย ออกมา · เลิก ซ่อนเร้น
bplòi òk maa · lêrk sôn ráyn
Released, stop hiding
Turn away and slam the door!
เดิน กลับ หลังหมด สิ้น เยื่อใย
dern glàp lăng mòt sîn yêua yai
Turn my back, no more relationship
I don't care what they're going to say
ฉัน ไม่ กลัว · ปล่อย ให้ เขา พูด ไป
chăn mâi glua · bplòi hâi kăo pôot bpai
I’m not afraid let they're going to say
Let the storm rage on
พัด ให้ โหมกระหน่ำ
pát hâi hŏhm grà-nàm
Let the storm rage on
The cold never bothered me anyway.
ความหนาว ไม่ ทำให้เดือดร้อน สักเท่า ไหร่
kwaam năao mâi tam hâi dèuat rón sàk tâo rài
The cold doesn't trouble me so much﻿
It's funny how some distance
มอง อะไร ยามไกลห่าง
mong a-rai yaam glai hàang
Looking at everything from the far distance
Makes everything seem small
กลับ เห็น เล็กลง ไป เลย
glàp hĕn lék long bpai loie
they seemed to be so small
And the fears that once controlled me
ความ หวั่นไหว ที่ คอย เข้า ครอบงำ
kwaam wàn wăi têe koi kâo krôp ngam
The fears that once dominated me
Can't get to me at all!
กลับ ทำ ไม่ได้ ดั่ง เคย
glàp tam mâi dâai dàng koie
can't control me as before
It's time to see what I can do
สิ่งใหม่ ยัง รอ ให้ ลอง ให้รู้
sìng mài yang ror hâi long hâi róo
The new thing await to be tried, to be known
To test the limits and break through
จะ ไป สุดทาง ให้ ใคร ได้ ดู
jà bpai sùt taang hâi krai dâai doo
I'll go until the end of the way to let the people see
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
ฉีก กฎซ้ำซ้ำ · เลือก ทำ สิ่งใด
chèek gòt sám sám · lêuak tam sìng dai
Break the boring rules, choose what to do
I'm free!
อย่างใจ
yàang jai
as my heart wants!
Let it go, let it go!
ปล่อย มัน ไป · อย่าง ที่ เป็น
bplòi man bpai · yàang têe bpen
Let it go, as it should be
I am one with the wind and sky
เชื่อม ใจ ไปกับ ลม และ ฟ้า
chêuam jai bpai gàp lom láe fáa
Connect my heart with the wind and sky
Let it go, let it go!
ปล่อย ออกมา · เลิก ซ่อนเร้น
bplòi òk maa · lêrk sôn ráyn
Released, stop hiding
You'll never see me cry
เผชิญ มัน ด้วย ความกล้า
pà-chern man dûay kwaam glâa
Confront it with courage
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
ฉัน จะ ยืน · ตรงนี้ เรื่อยไป
chăn jà yeun · dtrong née rêuay bpai
I will stand here forever
Let the storm rage on...
พัด ให้ โหมกระหน่ำ
pát hâi hŏhm grà-nàm
Let the storm rage on
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
พลัง ใน กาย ล่อง ลมลอยฟ้า ลงมา สู่ ดิน
pá-lang nai gaai lông lom loi fáa long maa sòo din
The power in my body floats through the wind from the sky to the ground
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
พลังในใจ แทรก ใน เกล็ด น้ำแข็ง ล้อมรอบ กาย ไม่ส ­ ิ้น
pá-lang nai jai sâek nai glèt nám kăeng lóm rôp gaai ไม่ส ­ ิ้น
The power in my heart infiltrate inside the flakes ice around me endlessly
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
ผลึก ความคิด ผุด เป็น เกล็ดใส ไร้ ความกังขา
pà-lèuk kwaam kít pùt bpen glèt săi rái kwaam gang-kăa
The thought crystallize into the clear flakes, doubtlessly
I'm never going back
ไม่ ขอ คิด หวนคืน ไป
mâi kŏr kít hŭan keun bpai
I don't want to go back,
The past is in the past!
ความหลัง ไม่อาจ คืน มา
kwaam lăng mâi àat keun maa
the past can't come back
Let it go, let it go!
เป็นตัว เรา · อย่าง ที่ เป็น
bpen dtua rao · yàang têe bpen
Be myself as how I am
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
ขอ ทะยาน ดั่ง ตะวัน ส่อง ฟ้า
kŏr tá-yaan dàng dtà-wan sòng fáa
I will soar like the sun is shining in the sky
Let it go, let it go!
ปล่อย ออกมา · เลิก ซ่อนเร้น
bplòi òk maa · lêrk sôn ráyn
Released, stop hiding
That perfect girl is gone
เด็กดี ไม่เห็น มีค่า
dèk dee mâi hĕn mee kâa
The good girl is worthless
Here I stand in the light of day
ฉัน จะ ยืน · เด่น ใน แสงแรงกล้า
chăn jà yeun · dàyn nai săeng raeng glâa
I will stand prominently under the strong light
Let the storm rage on!
พัดกระหน่ำ เข้าไป
pát grà-nàm kâo bpai
Let the storm rage on
The cold never bothered me anyway.
ความหนาว ไม่ ทำให้เดือดร้อน ซักเท่า ไหร่
kwaam năao mâi tam hâi dèuat rón sák tâo rài
The cold doesn't trouble me so much﻿